Joshua R. Koch

joshua.koch98@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/joshuakoch5697 (412) 498-6664 2578 Siesta Drive, Pittsburgh, PA 15241

OBJECTIVE:

I am searching for a full-time engineering position in the Boston area. Currently, I am working on a one-year contract, which expires on July 20th, 2021. My professional experience has awarded me competencies such as customer focus, drive for results, and collaboration. I am team oriented with outstanding interpersonal skills that welcomes and accepts input from others.

EDUCATION:

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

The Pennsylvania State University, University Park, PA GPA: **3.4/4.0**

Graduation Date: May 8, 2020

Dean's List Honors: Spring 2020, Fall 2019, Spring 2019 & Fall 2017

Relevant Courses

Engineering Writing
Product Design & Manufacturing
Design Methodology
EDSGN Analysis CAD

Dynamic Systems
Material Science
Mechatronics
Fluid Mechanics

SKILLS:

Oral & Written Communication, 3D & 2D Modelling, FEA, GD&T, MATLAB

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Validation Engineer (Contractor).....July 2020 – Present Bayer Pharmaceuticals, Indianola, PA

- Draft and execute validation protocols on automated syringe assembly lines
- Complete validation processes on new high-volume manufacturing line
- Design & implement mechanical fixtures to automated plant machinery
- Train production personnel to execute validation protocols

Manufacturing Engineering Intern. May 2019 – Aug. 2019 Bayer Pharmaceuticals, Indianola, PA

- Completed verification & validation processes of automated HFFS equipment
- Researched & tested process improvements to package testing protocols
- Designed & implemented mechanical fixtures to automated packaging machines
- Drafted and reviewed changes to new and existing protocols

- Worked directly with customers to implement natural gas services to commercial and residential locations
- Designed precise pipeline extensions to deliver gas to customers
- Worked directly with construction managers to implement designs
- Created AutoCAD drawings and SAP estimates for each project

LEADERSHIP & INVOLVEMENT:

Vice President, Theta Chi Fraternity, Omega Chapter (2017-18) Member, Unmanned Aerial Systems Club (2019)

Secretary, Theta Chi Fraternity, Omega Chapter (2016-17)